<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Self Improvement on Shoonya</title>
    <link>/categories/self-improvement/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Self Improvement on Shoonya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 19:24:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the Coding Interview with Deliberate Practice</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-07-01-cracking-the-coding-interview-with-deliberate-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 19:24:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-07-01-cracking-the-coding-interview-with-deliberate-practice/</guid>
      <description>Given n non-negative integers representing an elevation map where the width of each bar is 1, compute how much water it is able to trap after raining.One of the first things you should do in interviews is ask clarifying questions. The first question would be, are you a water management company or a software company? Once the futility has been confirmed, you will ponder about the algorithm. Should I sort? Should I use a stack?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoicism in the times of COVID-19</title>
      <link>/posts/2020-06-18-stoicism-in-the-times-of-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 04:42:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2020-06-18-stoicism-in-the-times-of-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>It would be an understatement to say obstacles are all around for people who got affected by COVID-19, for businesses that got impacted, and for people who got laid off in a 3 minute Zoom callor an e-mail in the morning. What do you do when the black swan event of the century turns a normal day into a day where you wonder about how you are going to survive this crisis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Digital Minimalism by Cal Newport</title>
      <link>/posts/2019-03-07-book-review-digital-minimalism-by-cal-newport/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 11:34:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2019-03-07-book-review-digital-minimalism-by-cal-newport/</guid>
      <description>Every day I have an hour commute by BART – San Francisco Bay Area’s delightful transit system. When you are waiting for the train, there is a sight that will grab your attention every single day. Everyone is on the phone, mindlessly swiping gems on a game, binge-watching Netflix, and catching up with the latest on their favorite social media outlet. Caught up in their screens, it is fun to see people miss their stations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Lifelong Learning</title>
      <link>/2017/07/31/deliberate-lifelong-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 02:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/31/deliberate-lifelong-learning/</guid>
      <description>In an interview on the AI Podcast, Andrew Ng predicts that AI would be an essential part of our lives and it is going to transform the world, the way electricity did. A consequence of that is not that Skynet would activate, but many of the existing jobs would disappear. To survive, lifelong learning would become essential. Previously, we could learn something in college and ply trade based on that knowledge for decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Become an Expert</title>
      <link>/2017/07/01/the-best-way-to-become-an-expert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 20:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/01/the-best-way-to-become-an-expert/</guid>
      <description>In June 2017, Alex Honnold did something which no man had done before. He climbed El Capitan in Yosemite without any ropes. This free solo ascent of the 3000 ft rock formation without any fallback mechanism ranks as one of the greatest athletic feats ever. Equally interesting is the way Alex Honnold trained. He did 60 practice climbs on El Capitan. First, he rehearsed these climbs using rope. He memorized complex portions of the climb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9 Tips For Engineers For Learning Efficiently</title>
      <link>/2015/08/15/9-tips-for-engineers-for-learning-efficiently/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 04:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/15/9-tips-for-engineers-for-learning-efficiently/</guid>
      <description>In our software engineering careers, we switch jobs and end up working in a new domain. Some domains are easy to learn — the engineering might be hard — while others, especially those involving payments or stock exchanges (few areas where I have worked) take time to understand. There is another issue as you progress in your career: when you are fresh out of college, the brain is tuned to learning techniques, but after a few decades of work, you struggle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
