<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Work on Shoonya</title>
    <link>/tags/deep-work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Deep Work on Shoonya</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 02:33:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/deep-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate Lifelong Learning</title>
      <link>/2017/07/31/deliberate-lifelong-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 02:33:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/31/deliberate-lifelong-learning/</guid>
      <description>In an interview on the AI Podcast, Andrew Ng predicts that AI would be an essential part of our lives and it is going to transform the world, the way electricity did. A consequence of that is not that Skynet would activate, but many of the existing jobs would disappear. To survive, lifelong learning would become essential. Previously, we could learn something in college and ply trade based on that knowledge for decades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Best Way to Become an Expert</title>
      <link>/2017/07/01/the-best-way-to-become-an-expert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 20:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/01/the-best-way-to-become-an-expert/</guid>
      <description>In June 2017, Alex Honnold did something which no man had done before. He climbed El Capitan in Yosemite without any ropes. This free solo ascent of the 3000 ft rock formation without any fallback mechanism ranks as one of the greatest athletic feats ever. Equally interesting is the way Alex Honnold trained. He did 60 practice climbs on El Capitan. First, he rehearsed these climbs using rope. He memorized complex portions of the climb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Deep Work – 1</title>
      <link>/2017/03/15/doing-deep-work-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 05:03:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/15/doing-deep-work-1/</guid>
      <description>Doing deep work requires focus. You have to be free of distractions and have to be wise enough not to drown yourself in mindless web surfing. You should not end up as a slave to an attention grabbing algorithm run by a social media company. In the Ezra Klein podcast,Yuval Noah Harari, the author of Sapiens,talks about his technique for overcoming distraction I try to set my own agenda and not to allow technology to set the agenda for me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
